<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>Jelle's blog</title>
<link>http://jelle.aard.xyz/</link>
<atom:link href="http://jelle.aard.xyz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><description>Jelle's blog, ambivalently generated by HasClunk</description><item>
<title>Herding Cats</title>
<link>http://jelle.aard.xyz/posts/2015-07-25-herding_cats</link><guid>http://jelle.aard.xyz/posts/2015-07-25-herding_cats</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<!--
title: Herding Cats
categories: games
-->
<p>I have just started reading <a href="http://auntiepixelante.com/?p=1583">Rise of the Videogame Zinesters</a> by Anna Anthropy and while I was looking at the games she made I found this little puzzle gem in her list: <a href="http://www.puzzlescript.net/play.html?p=0ce1a363836151b78be0">Herding Cats</a>.</p>
<div class="figure">
<img src="/assets/herding_cats.png" />
</div>
<p>Herding Cats is a top down puzzler in the style of Sokoban/Paganitzu/Adventures of Lolo with a very neat twist. Instead of pushing boxes around and blocking baddies, you have to herd cats. The mechanic is as simple as it is tricky, because the cats stick to you once you get next to their block and they will remain by your side for the entire session. Thankfully you can undo moves, and - trust me - you will need this. You can easily end up with too many sticky cats, meaning you can't get past a narrow part.</p>
<p>I love the way the cats' furs change color each time you reload a level and I'm quite envious of the player's pink hair. Tried to do that once, but my hair's too dark to get properly blonde for coloring.</p>
<p>Herding Cats is pretty neat and difficult, but (thankfully) easy enough to finish in your average coffee break. The perfect kind of game for days like these when I'm surfing a deadline's waves like I never managed to pull of in California Games.</p>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>New blog</title>
<link>http://jelle.aard.xyz/posts/2015-07-21-new_blog</link><guid>http://jelle.aard.xyz/posts/2015-07-21-new_blog</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<!--
title: New blog
categories: general
-->
<p>Greetings and salutations visitor. This is my new weblog, using the brand spanking new static weblog generator <a href="https://github.com/jellehermsen/HasClunk">HasClunk</a>.</p>
<p>I actually wanted to use <a href="http://jaspervdj.be/hakyll/">Hakyll</a>, but couldn't get it setup because of the dreaded Cabal dependecy hell raining down errors on me. Usually when such a thing happens, I will just keep on twiddling till it's done, but not this time. I figured I could build my own static blog generator quickly, so I just went at it.</p>
<p>HasClunk supports posts, pages, categories and RSS. It's everything I need at the moment. I might add <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gopher_(protocol)">Gopher</a> support later on, because that kind of fits the <a href="http://aard.xyz">Aardvark community</a>. Aardvark is a network of people who (mostly) met at <a href="http://sdf.org">SDF</a> and started their own IRC server when SDF was having some downtime because of DDOS attacks. <a href="http://cultofbob.com">Nismorack</a> calls us paleotechnologists and this makes sense, because most of use love to use terminals instead of desktop environments, and we're working on our own BBS. You can even visit us on <a href="gopher://aard.xyz/">Gopher</a>.</p>
<p>I'm kind of a Haskell and general code geek, so much of this blog will be about those subjects. I'm also working on game ideas that I would love to see come to life, but don't hold your breath for them. In the mean time I work as a freelance medical programmer and I like playing and reading about indie games. The indie game scene is awesome and I'm a big fan of the growing diversity, gripping games out of the cold dead white masculine hands and make them rainbow colored!</p>
]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>